Preliminary Inventory of the Charles F. Kettering Foundation records
Hoover Institution Archives
Charles F. Kettering Foundation records
1933-1984
85001
Charles F. Kettering Foundation.
484 manuscript boxes, 2 oversize boxes, 19 motion picture film reels, 1 phonorecord, 7 linear feet. (203.5 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, memoranda, reports, grant proposals, minutes, financial records, studies, printed matter, and audiovisual material, relating to research in the fields of international affairs, science, education, and urban affairs.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1985.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Socrates is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical/Historical Note
American philanthropic foundation.
Scope and Content of Collection
Correspondence, memoranda, reports, grant proposals, minutes, financial records, studies, printed matter, and audiovisual material, relating to research in the fields of international affairs, science, education, and urban affairs.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Education.; Endowments--United States.; International cooperation.; International education.; International relations.; Science.; Phonorecords; Moving pictures
Collection Contents
- Central Administration
  - Accounting
    - General Files (Box 1)
    - Budgets: I/D/E/A (Institute for Development of Educational Activities, Inc.), 1966-1972 (Box 2)
    - Budgets: I/D/E/A, 1973-1975 (Box 3)
    - Budgets: I/D/E/A, 1976-1979 (Box 4)
    - Budgets: CFKF (Charles F. Kettering Foundation), 1969-1971 (Box 5)
    - Budgets: CFKF, 1971-1974 (Box 6)
    - Budgets: CFKF, 1974-1975 (Box 7)
    - Budgets: CFKF, 1976-1979 (Box 8)
    - Budgets: CFKF, 1979-1981 (Box 9)
    - Budgets: CFKF, 1981-1982 (Box 10)
  - Personnel: Staff Directories (Box 11)
- Exploration Fund (Box 12)
- Planning Office, Planning Documents
  - Planning Book, 1970-1975 (Box 13)
  - Planning Book, 1975-1981 (Box 14)
  - Program Reviews and Briefing Materials, 1978-1982 (Box 15)
  - Monthly Reports, September 1972-March 1973 (Box 16)
  - Monthly Reports, April 1973-October 1973 (Box 17)
  - Monthly Reports, November 1973-June 1974 (Box 18)
  - Monthly Reports, July 1974-January 1975 (Box 19)
  - Monthly Reports, February 1975-August 1975 (Box 20)
  - Monthly Reports, October 1975-April 1976 (Box 21)
  - Monthly Reports, May 1976-February 1977 (Box 22)
  - Monthly Reports, March 1977-September 1977 (Box 23)
  - Monthly Reports, October 1977-June 1978 (Box 24)
  - Monthly Reports, August 1978-March 1980 (Box 25)
  - Quarterly Reports, March 1977-June 1981 (Box 26)
  - Semi-Annual Reports, Fall 1981 (Box 26)
  - Planning Committee Minutes
    - Fortnightly Group Minutes, July 1971-April 1972 (Box 27)
    - Development Committee, 5 January 1971-15 June 1971 (Box 27)
    - Development Committee, 24 June 1971-2 June 1972 (Box 28)
    - Development Committee, 28 June 1972- 12 February 1973 (Box 29)
    - Development Committee, 19 February 1973-16 July 1973 (Box 30)
    - Development Committee, 30 July1973-19 August 1974 (Box 31)
    - Development Committee, 30 September 1974-19 July 1976 (Box 32)
    - Development Committee, 1 September 1976-2 November 1976 (Box 33)
  - Executive Staff Committee
    - Executive Staff Committee Meetings, December 1978-March 1981 (Box 34)
    - Planning Group Notes, March-April, 1981 (Box 34)
    - Staff Group Meeting Notes, May 1981-December 1981 (Box 34)
    - Project Review Panel Meetings, 23 April 1979 - 5 May 1981 (Box 35)
    - Development/Planning Committee General Files, 1971-1973 (Box 35)
    - Executive Staff Committee Files, 1980-1981 (Box 35)
  - Winston O. Franklin, Vice President for Planning
    - A-B (Box 36)
    - B-C (Box 37)
    - C (Box 38)
    - C-D (Box 39)
    - D-G (Box 40)
    - H-L (Box 41)
    - L-N (Box 42)
    - O-P (Box 43)
    - P-S (Box 44)
    - T-Z (Box 45)
- James L. Caplinger, Senior Program Officer for the Social Sciences
  - A-Z (Box 46)
- Kent Collins, Director, Exploration Fund
  - A-C (Box 47)
  - C-E (Box 48)
  - E-G (Box 49)
  - G-H (Box 50)
  - L-P (Box 51)
  - P-Z (Box 52)
- James M. Read, Vice-President for Program Management
  - A-B (Box 53)
  - B-C (Box 54)
  - C (Box 55)
  - C (Box 56)
  - C-D (Box 57)
  - D (Box 58)
  - E-F (Box 59)
  - G-I (Box 60)
  - I (Box 61)
  - I-K (Box 62)
  - L-O (Box 63)
  - P-S (Box 64)
  - S-U (Box 65)
  - V-Z (Box 66)
  - Correspondence, 1970-1977 (Box 66)
- Phillips Ruopp, Director, International Affairs
  - A-F (Box 67)
  - F-L (Box 68)
  - M-O (Box 69)
  - O (Box 70)
  - P-R (Box 71)
  - R-T (Box 72)
  - V-Z (Box 73)
  - Correspondence (Box 73)
- William Shaw, Research Assistant
  - A-H (Box 74)
  - H-Z (Box 75)
- Robert C. Chollar, President and Chairman of the Board (Box 76-120)
  Meeting Minutes, agendas, and reports for conferences, grant proposals and reccomendations, planning documents, reports, correspondence, trip schedules and background materials.
- Domestic Policy Association
  - Publications (Box 121)
  - National Issues Forum, organizational material and reports (Box 122)
  - Newsletters and press releases (Box 123)
- Communications
  - Tapes by Charles F. Kettering (Box 124)
  - Photographs (Box 125)
  - News releases and awards (Box 126)
  - Remarks and speeches, Robert C. Chollar (Box 127)
- Urban Affairs
  - A-C (Box 128)
  - C-H (Box 129)
  - H (Box 130)
  - H-I (Box 131)
  - I-M (Box 132)
  - M (Box 133)
  - M-N (Box 134)
  - N-P (Box 135)
  - P-U (Box 136)
  - U (Box 137)
  - U-Z (Box 138)
  - Administration (Box 139)
  - James Kunde, Director, Urban Affairs (Box 140-141)
  - Wayne Howell, Program Manager, Citizen's Involvement Project (Box 142)
  - Citizen's Involvement Network, Administration (Box 143)
  - Daniel E. Barry, Senior Program Officer (Box 144)
  - Grant Files (Box 145-150)
- Science and Technology
  - Eric Walther, Project Manager (Box 151)
  - General (Box 152-153)
  - Administration (Box 154-155)
  - Howard A. Tanner, Director of Research, Kettering Lab, Early Grants (Box 156-157)
  - Edwin H. Vause, Vice-President, Science and Technology
    - General, circa 1975-1978 (Box 158-162)
    - I/D/E/A (Institute for Development of Educational Activities, Inc.) A-H, circa late 1960s-early 1970s (Box 163)
    - I/D/E/A, I-Z, circa late 1960s-early 1970s (Box 164)
  - Agribusiness Advisory Board, Tapes and Charts (Box 165)
  - Agribusiness Advisory Board, Newsletters (Box 166)
  - Kettering Magnetics Lab (Box 167)
  - Boss Ket project - oral history about Charles F. Kettering (Box 168)
  - Ephemera (Box 169)
  - Twentieth Century Fund on Foundation Performance (Box 170)
  - Laboratory reprints (Box 171)
  - Grants, slides and film (Box 172-174)
  - I/D/E/A (Institute for Development of Educational Activities, Inc.) (Box 175)
  - Administration (Box 176)
  - Administration/Miscellany (Box 177)
  - Administration/Admin Council Minutes and Notes (Box 178)
  - Administration/Education Program Council Meeting Minutes and Notes (Box 179)
  - Samuel Sava, Vice-President for Educational Activities, CFKF
    - A-E (Box 180)
    - E-I (Box 181)
    - I/D/E/A (Box 182)
    - I/D/E/A - IGE (Box 183)
    - IGE (Box 184)
    - I-O (Box 185)
    - T-Z (Box 186)
    - Correspondence and Memos, A-T (Box 187)
    - Correspondence and Memos, U-Z (Box 188)
    - Conferences and Projects, A-E (Box 189)
    - Conferences and Projects, F-I (Box 190)
    - Conferences and Projects, I-W (Box 191)
  - Speeches and Papers (Box 192)
  - Charles Willis, Program Director (Box 193-197)
  - John Bahner, Director, Innovative Programs (Box 198)
  - Charles Willis, Program Director (Box 199)
  - Gallup Kettering Education Polls, 1969-1981
    - Summaries and publications (Box 200)
    - Educational Surveys, 1977-1981 (Box 201)
    - Educational Surveys, 1969-1976 (Box 202)
- Special Institute (Fellows) (Box 203)
- Charles F. Kettering II, Obituaries (Box 204)
- International Affairs
  - A (Box 205)
  - A-B (Box 206)
  - C (Box 207)
  - C-D (Box 208)
  - E-G (Box 209)
  - G-I (Box 210)
  - I (Box 211)
  - I (Box 212)
  - I-J (Box 213)
  - K-L (Box 214)
  - L-O (Box 215)
  - O-P (Box 216)
  - P (Box 217)
  - P (Box 218)
  - P-R (Box 219)
  - R-S (Box 220)
  - S-T (Box 221)
  - T (Box 222)
  - T-Z (Box 223)
  - Letters of Agreement (Box 224)
  - Grants (Box 225-251)
- Additional Materials (Box 252-483)
  Aproximately every fifth box was chosen to give a represenative sample of the contents of otherwise unidenfified boxes remaining in this collection
  - Trustees Ad Hoc Committee on International Affairs (Box 252)
  - Press releases, Soviet-American writer's conference, by-laws, miscellany (Box 256)
  - NATO, Canadian trade conference (Box 261)
  - Articles on China (Box 266)
  - China, 1965-1971 (Box 271)
  - Board meeting minutes (Box 276)
  - Cholar, General E-G (?) (Box 281)
  - Science and Technology Grants (Box 286)
  - ED (?) Grants (Box 291-293)
  - Miscellaneous publications (Box 296)
  - Urban Affairs, miscellaneous (Box 301)
  - I/D/E/A (Institute for Development of Educational Activities, Inc.) publications, G-IGE (Box 306)
  - Grants (Box 311)
  - Publications and Reports (Box 316)
  - Personnel, purchase orders, archives proposal, administrative miscellany (Box 321)
  - Publications (Box 326)
  - Grants (Box 331-336)
  - Charles F. Kettering 1876-1958, by Stuart W. Leslie (dissertation) (Box 341)
  - Chollar, General O-Z (Box 346)
  - Communications: briefing materials, president's 10 year review, CFKF 1980 annual report (Box 351)
  - Notebooks (Box 356)
  - UNA-USA Parallel Studies Program with the Soviet Union (Box 361)
  - ER (Exploratory Research?) Grants (Box 366)
  - CI (Citizen's Involvement?) Grants (Box 371)
  - I/D/E/A Files (Box 382)
  - Tapes (Box 387)
  - Videotapes (Box 388-389)
  - Kettering Information (Box 392)
  - Photographs (Box 397)
  - Tapes, slides, and film (Box 399)
  - Grants (Box 403)
  - CI Grants (Box 407)
  - Publications (Box 412)
  - Publications (Box 417)
  - Publications (Box 422)
  - Publications (Box 427)
  - Publications (Box 432)
  - Publications (Box 437)
  - Publications (Box 442)
  - Publications (Box 447)
  - Publications (Box 452)
  - Publications (Box 457)
  - Publications (Box 462)
  - Tapes (Box 467)
  - Publications (Box 472)
  - Publications (Box 477)
  - Tapes and slides (Box 482)
- Sound Recordings (Phonorecord), 1955 November 21
  - Sound recordings of Charles Kettering pondering education, 1955 November 21
    Conditions Governing Access note
    Use copy reference number: 85001_a_0002809
    Scope and Contents note
    The first recording concerns specialized vs. broad education as applied to innovation. The second concerns co-operative education. 1 disc
- Motion picture films (Film shelf, On shelf)
  For information on getting a use copy of motion picture films, please contact the Hoover Institution Archives
  - "I/D/E/A - 'Unit Meeting'" 16mm film, 1970 (Box On Shelf)
  - "One at a Time Together 'Revised Elementary'" 16mm film, undated (Box On Shelf)
  - "Somebody Special," 16mm film, undated (Box On Shelf)
  - "Summer Children," 1500 ft., 16mm film, 1973 (Box Film Shelf)
  - "Survival of Spaceship Earth," 16mm film, 1973 (Box Film Shelf)
  - "The League Pt.2 A Matter of Trust," 16mm film, undated (Box Film Shelf)
  - "Hi, School!" 16mm film, undated (Box Film Shelf)
  - "School Boards in Crisis," 16mm film, undated (Box Film Shelf)
  - "Yugoslavia A Land of Contrasts," 16mm film, undated (Box Film Shelf)
  - "Learning How to Learn A British Junior Classroom," 900 ft., 16mm film, undated (Box Film Shelf)
  - "Learning Through Inquiry," 16mm film, undated (Box Film Shelf)
  - "Change Training Teachers for Innovation," 16mm film, undated (Box Film Shelf)
  - "The Strategy The League - Pt 1," 2 reels, 16mm film, undated (Box Film Shelf)
  - "Whisper of Dissent," 1200 ft., 16mm film, undated (Box Film Shelf)
  - "Strategies of Small Group Learning," 16mm film, undated (Box Film Shelf)
  - "Try it Sometime The League Pt III," 16mm film, undated (Box Film Shelf)
  - "High School Reform," 16mm film, undated (Box Film Shelf)
  - "I Just Wanted You to Know How Well Rhonda is Doing in School Part IV - The League," 16mm film, undated (Box Film Shelf)
  - Unidentified film, 780 ft., 16mm film, 1973 (Box Film Shelf)
  - Unidentified film, 950 ft., 16mm film, 1973 (Box Film Shelf)
  - Unidentified film, 990 ft., 16mm film, 1973 (Box Film Shelf)
  - Unidentified film, 900 ft., 16mm film, undated (Box Film Shelf)